<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<language id="44">
  <page id="899900" title="Gatefall Chronicles" descr="Gatefall Chronicles custom Timelines campaign" voice="no">
    <t id="1">Gatefall 01: Under the Surface</t>
    <t id="2">You and a Terran wingman have just come through the gate and are heading deeper into the Mists of Artemis to drop an advanced satellite. What should have been a routine recon run turns into something a whole lot stranger—something tied to both the Xenon and the Kha'ak.</t>
    <t id="3">Behind the anomalous signal and the mass jump signatures, something far worse is brewing.</t>
    <t id="4">Phase 1 Demo</t>
    <t id="11">Mission</t>
    <t id="12">Wingman</t>
    <t id="13">Ship AI</t>
    <t id="14">Player</t>
    <t id="15">Wingman</t>
    <t id="16">Outpost Administrator</t>
    <t id="17">TER Outpost</t>
    <t id="18">Anomalous Signal</t>
    <t id="19">Paradigm Command</t>
    <t id="101">Mists of Artemis Recon Operation.</t>
    <t id="102">Investigate local Kha'ak hive activity</t>
    <t id="103">Do not engage Xenon capital forces unless absolutely necessary.</t>
    <t id="111">The Sunborn Militia has been contracted by Terran border intelligence to verify changes in Kha'ak hive activity in the Mists of Artemis.</t>
    <t id="112">Katana flight ordered into the Mists of Artemis</t>
    <t id="113">Deploy recon satellite, gather hive data, and pull out</t>
    <t id="201">Investigate the Mists of Artemis</t>
    <t id="202">The Sunborn Militia has been contracted by Terran border intelligence to verify changes in Kha'ak hive activity in the Mists of Artemis. The mission is risky, but the Intervention Corps will not divert major assets for a target this low on their list.</t>
    <t id="211">Fly to the deployment area and place the advanced satellite</t>
    <t id="212">Destroy the Xenon patrol</t>
    <t id="213">Approach the anomalous signal</t>
    <t id="214">Reach the TER outpost</t>
    <t id="215">Defend the TER outpost until the Intervention Corps arrives</t>
    <t id="501">Finally lost the Xenon. Took long enough.</t>
    <t id="502">Who the hell decided to send us to a place like this? Shouldn't this be an Intervention Corps job?</t>
    <t id="503">We're deep in Xenon territory. If the Corps wants to push in here, they're gonna have to pay for it in blood.</t>
    <t id="504">So what exactly are we doing again?</t>
    <t id="505">According to Shiratori: head to the marked area, drop a long-range satellite, confirm hive activity, then get back to Saturn Station and grab a drink.</t>
    <t id="506">Yeah... if it were ever that easy.</t>
    <t id="511">Satellite's down. Ship AI, start the readout.</t>
    <t id="512">Receiving telemetry now. Estimated completion time: twenty seconds.</t>
    <t id="513">Once the numbers come in, we can call it a day. Wonder if the beer festival at Saturn Station's still on...</t>
    <t id="514">Warning: Xenon vessels detected ahead. Range: thirty kilometres.</t>
    <t id="515">Xenon...? No way.</t>
    <t id="518">Doesn't matter. Weapons hot.</t>
    <t id="521">That's done. Ship AI, start parsing the satellite data.</t>
    <t id="522">Parsing now.</t>
    <t id="523">No qualifying Kha'ak station detected in the vicinity.</t>
    <t id="524">No qualifying station? Wasn't this supposed to be the biggest Kha'ak hive in the whole damned universe?</t>
    <t id="525">Maybe our coordinates are off. Widen the search.</t>
    <t id="526">Search radius expanded. Wreckage detected: Kha'ak Ravager-class guardian. No hive structure detected.</t>
    <t id="527">A Ravager... wreck? You're saying something killed it?</t>
    <t id="528">Unable to identify the attacker. Non-Kha'ak energy residue detected.</t>
    <t id="529">Xenon?</t>
    <t id="530">Residual signal shows partial overlap with Xenon energy signatures. Unknown spatial-fold readings also present.</t>
    <t id="531">Spatial-fold readings? What the hell are the Xenon up to?</t>
    <t id="532">See if there's anything else in there.</t>
    <t id="533">Anomalous signal detected in the distance. Signal pattern does not match a gate, accelerator, or conventional Kha'ak jump residue.</t>
    <t id="534">Mark it. We take a look, then we get the hell out.</t>
    <t id="541">That's a Xenon I... Why the hell is there a Xenon capital ship out here?</t>
    <t id="542">The Xenon don't usually send an I somewhere like this unless...</t>
    <t id="543">Warning: high-energy spatial fold detected.</t>
    <t id="544">What the hell is happening?</t>
    <t id="545">Unable to localise. The signal is coming from the entire debris field.</t>
    <t id="546">Where... where are we?</t>
    <t id="547">Star map recalibration complete. Current position: Savage Spur I.</t>
    <t id="548">Savage Spur I?! That's a Xenon core sector! We were just in the Mists of Artemis—</t>
    <t id="549">Inference: this ship was dragged in by an anomalous spatial fold.</t>
    <t id="550">So the Xenon got jump tech out of that Kha'ak hive... If there are Xenon forces outside the gate network—</t>
    <t id="551">Forget that. Look up ahead.</t>
    <t id="552">Multiple large ship groups detected exiting spatial fold.</t>
    <t id="553">We can't stay here. Savage Spur I has a one-way accelerator to Savage Spur II. There's a TER outpost on the other side.</t>
    <t id="554">...Right. Move. Now.</t>
    <t id="555">Hold on—something's happening.</t>
    <t id="556">That many I's... There aren't even that many inside the gate network...</t>
    <t id="561">This is the Savage Spur II outpost. Unauthorised vessels, identify yourselves immediately. Wait... Sunborn Militia? Weren't you assigned to the Mists of Artemis?</t>
    <t id="562">No time. The Xenon are coming.</t>
    <t id="563">Uploading sensor records now.</t>
    <t id="564">...Data received. Damn it. The defense crews are all back at Saturn Station getting drunk.</t>
    <t id="565">Well, we're screwed. Maybe we should just run for it—</t>
    <t id="566">Ten minutes! Just give me ten damn minutes! The Defense Minister said that after ten minutes, either the fleet gets here or his head rolls—one of the two!</t>
    <t id="567">Ten minutes? ...Fine. Let's just hope it's the fleet.</t>
    <t id="568">Warning: extra-large vessel signature detected. Identified as Xenon I.</t>
    <t id="569">No. No, no, no... that's an I.</t>
    <t id="570">Attention: Xenon K closing on the station.</t>
    <t id="571">We don't have the firepower to break a K's shields. Hit the engines—keep it off the station!</t>
    <t id="572">Warning: extra-large vessel signature detected. Identified as Xenon I.</t>
    <t id="573">No. No, no, no... that's an I.</t>
    <t id="574">We're done. The outpost is finished this time.</t>
    <t id="576">This is the Terran Intervention Corps battleship Paradigm. Sorry we're late. Looks like things got ugly. More ships are coming through the gate behind us.</t>
    <t id="577">Threat eliminated. Repeat, threat eliminated. Stand down from red alert. All units, maintain patrol status.</t>
    <t id="578">To the two Sunborn Militia pilots: you have our thanks. We've already pulled the sensor records from your ship computers.</t>
    <t id="579">The Xenon are using Kha'ak jump technology. If they can bring in reinforcements from outside the gate network, then the whole of human civilisation is in deep trouble.</t>
    <t id="580">Drinks at Saturn are on me, so help yourselves. Just don't overdo it—the Intervention Corps command staff and the Defense Ministry still want a full report from both of you.</t>
    <t id="581">Warning: first Xenon attack wing is closing fast.</t>
    <t id="582">At least these are still the small ones.</t>
    <t id="1001">Phase 1 Demo Complete</t>
    <t id="1002">You completed the Phase 1 demo of Under the Surface: scouting the Mists of Artemis, breaking out through Savage Spur, and helping the TER outpost hold until Paradigm arrived.</t>
    <t id="1003">Demo Failed</t>
    <t id="1004">You failed to complete the Phase 1 demo of Under the Surface.</t>
  </page>
</language>
