<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<language id="44">
  <page id="899900" title="Gatefall Chronicles" descr="Gatefall Chronicles custom Timelines campaign" voice="no">
    <t id="1">Gatefall 01: Under the Surface</t>
    <t id="2">Background: The Xenon have seized Kha'ak jump technology and are using it to funnel forces from beyond the gate network into known space, setting a chain of disasters in motion. You are about to uncover the first piece of their plot.\n\nGameplay: Pilot a frigate against fighter-class ships, defend a station, and cripple the engines of enemy capital ships.</t>
    <t id="3">You are a pilot with the Sunborn Militia, entering the Mists of Artemis to deploy a long-range reconnaissance satellite.</t>
    <t id="4">Phase 1 Demo</t>

    <t id="11">Mission</t>
    <t id="12">Wingman</t>
    <t id="14">Player</t>
    <t id="15">Wingman</t>
    <t id="16">Outpost Administrator</t>
    <t id="17">TER Outpost</t>
    <t id="18">Anomalous Signal</t>
    <t id="19">TER Paradigm</t>
    <t id="20">Sunborn Militia Katana</t>

    <t id="101">Mists of Artemis Recon Operation.</t>
    <t id="102">Investigate local Kha'ak hive activity.</t>
    <t id="103">Do not engage Xenon capital forces unless absolutely necessary.</t>
    <t id="111">The Sunborn Militia has been contracted by Terran border intelligence to verify changes in Kha'ak hive activity in the Mists of Artemis.</t>
    <t id="112">Katana flight ordered into the Mists of Artemis.</t>
    <t id="113">Deploy recon satellite, gather hive data, and pull out.</t>

    <t id="201">Investigate the Mists of Artemis.</t>
    <t id="202">The Sunborn Militia has been contracted by Terran border intelligence to verify changes in Kha'ak hive activity in the Mists of Artemis. The mission is risky, but the Intervention Corps will not divert major assets for a target this low on their list.</t>
    <t id="211">Fly to the deployment area and place the advanced satellite.</t>
    <t id="212">Destroy the Xenon patrol.</t>
    <t id="213">Approach the anomalous signal.</t>
    <t id="214">Reach the TER outpost.</t>
    <t id="215">Defend the TER outpost until the Intervention Corps arrives.</t>

    <t id="501">Finally shook the Xenon. Took long enough.</t>
    <t id="502">Who the hell decided to send us somewhere like this? Shouldn't this be an Intervention Corps problem?</t>
    <t id="503">We're deep in Xenon territory. If the Corps wants to push in here, they'll have to bleed for it.</t>
    <t id="504">So what exactly are we doing here again?</t>
    <t id="505">According to Shiratori: head to the marked area, drop a long-range satellite, confirm hive activity, then get back to Saturn Station and grab a drink.</t>
    <t id="506">Yeah... if only it were ever that simple.</t>

    <t id="511">Satellite deployed. Ship AI, begin the readout.</t>
    <t id="512">Receiving telemetry now. Estimated completion time: twenty seconds.</t>
    <t id="513">Once the numbers are in, we can head home. Wonder if the beer festival at Saturn Station is still going...</t>
    <t id="514">Warning: Xenon vessels detected ahead. Range: thirty kilometres.</t>
    <t id="515">Xenon...? No way.</t>
    <t id="518">Doesn't matter. Weapons hot.</t>

    <t id="521">That's done. Ship AI, start parsing the satellite data.</t>
    <t id="522">Parsing now.</t>
    <t id="523">No qualifying Kha'ak station detected in the vicinity.</t>
    <t id="524">Nothing? Wasn't this supposed to be one of the biggest Kha'ak hives in the whole damned universe?</t>
    <t id="525">Maybe our coordinates are off. Widen the search.</t>
    <t id="526">Search radius expanded. Wreckage detected: Kha'ak Ravager-class guardian. No hive structure detected.</t>
    <t id="527">A Ravager... wreck? You're saying something killed it?</t>
    <t id="528">Unable to identify the attacker. Non-Kha'ak energy residue detected.</t>
    <t id="529">Xenon?</t>
    <t id="530">Residual signal shows partial overlap with Xenon energy signatures. Unknown spatial-fold readings also present.</t>
    <t id="531">Spatial-fold readings? What the hell are the Xenon up to?</t>
    <t id="532">See if there's anything else in there.</t>
    <t id="533">Anomalous signal detected in the distance. Signal pattern does not match a gate, accelerator, or conventional Kha'ak jump residue.</t>
    <t id="534">Mark it. We take a look, then we get out.</t>

    <t id="541">That's a Xenon I... Why the hell is a Xenon capital ship all the way out here?</t>
    <t id="542">The Xenon don't usually send an I somewhere like this unless...</t>
    <t id="543">Warning: high-energy spatial fold detected.</t>
    <t id="544">What the hell is happening?</t>
    <t id="545">Unable to localise. The signal is coming from the entire debris field.</t>
    <t id="546">Where... where are we?</t>
    <t id="547">Star map recalibration complete. Current position: Savage Spur I.</t>
    <t id="548">Savage Spur I?! That's a Xenon core sector! We were just in the Mists of Artemis...</t>
    <t id="549">Inference: this ship was dragged in by an anomalous spatial fold.</t>
    <t id="550">So the Xenon got jump technology out of that Kha'ak hive... If there are Xenon forces outside the gate network...</t>
    <t id="551">Forget that. Look ahead.</t>
    <t id="552">Multiple large ship groups detected exiting spatial fold.</t>
    <t id="553">We can't stay here. Savage Spur I has a one-way accelerator to Savage Spur II. There's a TER outpost on the other side.</t>
    <t id="554">...Right. Move. Now.</t>
    <t id="555">Hold on... something's happening.</t>
    <t id="556">That many I-class ships... There aren't even this many in the whole gate network...</t>

    <t id="561">This is the Savage Spur II outpost. Unauthorised vessels, identify yourselves immediately. Wait... Sunborn Militia? Weren't you assigned to the Mists of Artemis?</t>
    <t id="562">No time to explain. The Xenon are coming.</t>
    <t id="563">Uploading sensor records now.</t>
    <t id="564">...Data received. Damn it. The defence crews are all back at Saturn Station getting drunk.</t>
    <t id="565">Then we're screwed. Maybe we should just run for it...</t>
    <t id="566">Ten minutes! Just buy us ten damn minutes! The Defence Minister said that after ten minutes, either the fleet gets here or his head rolls; one of the two!</t>
    <t id="567">Ten minutes? ...Fine. Let's just hope it's the fleet.</t>
    <t id="568">Warning: extra-large vessel signature detected. Identified as Xenon I.</t>
    <t id="569">No. No, no, no... that's an I.</t>
    <t id="570">Attention: Xenon K closing on the station.</t>
    <t id="571">We don't have the firepower to break a K's shields. Hit the engines and keep it off the station!</t>
    <t id="572">Warning: extra-large vessel signature detected. Identified as Xenon I.</t>
    <t id="573">No. No, no, no... that's another I.</t>
    <t id="574">We're done. The outpost is finished this time.</t>
    <t id="576">This is the Terran Intervention Corps battleship Paradigm. Sorry we're late. Looks like you've had quite the party. More reinforcements are already coming through the gate.</t>
    <t id="577">Threat eliminated. Repeat, threat eliminated. Stand down from red alert. All units, maintain patrol status.</t>
    <t id="578">To the two Sunborn Militia pilots: you have our thanks. We've already pulled the sensor records from your ship computers.</t>
    <t id="579">The Xenon are using Kha'ak jump technology. If they can keep pulling reinforcements in from beyond the gate network, human civilisation is well and truly screwed.</t>
    <t id="580">Drinks at Saturn are on me, so help yourselves. Just don't overdo it. The Intervention Corps staff and the Defence Ministry still want a full report from both of you.</t>
    <t id="581">Warning: first Xenon attack wing is closing fast.</t>
    <t id="582">At least these are still the small ones.</t>

    <t id="1001">Phase 1 Demo Complete</t>
    <t id="1002">You completed the Phase 1 demo of Under the Surface: scouting the Mists of Artemis, breaking out through Savage Spur, and helping the TER outpost hold until Paradigm arrived.</t>
    <t id="1003">Demo Failed</t>
    <t id="1004">You failed to complete the Phase 1 demo of Under the Surface.</t>
    <t id="1005">Player Hull</t>
    <t id="1006">TER Outpost Hull</t>
  </page>

  <page id="899901" title="Gatefall Chronicles" descr="Gatefall Chronicles custom Timelines campaign 02" voice="no">
    <t id="1">Gatefall 02: Passing the Buck</t>
    <t id="2">Background: Using stolen jump technology, the Xenon are funnelling ever more forces into the gate network, and Tharka's Cascade is taking the brunt of it.\nSince HAT needed ARG's help to resolve the Scale Plate Pact crisis, it has effectively become an Argon vassal—one expected to pay in blood when asked. The 86th Escort Fleet is one such payment.\nThe 86th once saved your life. Now ARG means to spend them as cannon fodder, and you are determined to keep them alive, whatever the cost.\nGameplay: Command a frigate fleet remotely (OOS) and put its anti-fighter and anti-capital capabilities to the test.</t>
    <t id="3">Play as ARG commander Syme, directing HAT's 86th Escort Fleet from a rear command platform in Hatikvah's Choice as one crisis after another erupts in Tharka's Cascade.</t>
    <t id="4">Full Campaign Demo</t>

    <t id="11">ARG Rear Command Platform</t>
    <t id="12">Captain Rayna</t>
    <t id="13">Ship AI</t>
    <t id="14">Player</t>
    <t id="16">TEL Freighter</t>
    <t id="17">HAT Mining Guard Station</t>
    <t id="18">Profit Escort</t>
    <t id="19">HAT Miner</t>
    <t id="20">ARG Rear Command Platform</t>
    <t id="21">86th Escort Fleet Leader</t>
    <t id="22">HAT 86th Escort Fleet Cerberus</t>
    <t id="23">Frontier Commander</t>
    <t id="24">Staff Officer</t>
    <t id="25">Staff Officer</t>
    <t id="26">Satellite Deployment Point</t>
    <t id="27">Rear Platform Bar</t>
    <t id="28">Classified Database</t>
    <t id="29">Navigation Beacon Deployment Point</t>
    <t id="30">ZYA Dragon</t>
    <t id="31">ZYA Elephant Rescue Convoy</t>
    <t id="32">ZYA Weapon Component Factory</t>
    <t id="33">ZYA Hull Parts Factory Alpha</t>
    <t id="34">ZYA Hull Parts Factory Beta</t>
    <t id="35">ZYA Refined Metals Factory Alpha</t>
    <t id="36">ZYA Refined Metals Factory Beta</t>
    <t id="37">ZYA Weapon Component Factory Alpha</t>
    <t id="38">ZYA Weapon Component Factory Beta</t>
    <t id="39">ZYA Missile Component Factory Alpha</t>
    <t id="40">ZYA Missile Component Factory Beta</t>
    <t id="41">ZYA Scan Component Factory Alpha</t>
    <t id="42">ZYA Scan Component Factory Beta</t>
    <t id="43">ZYA Border Defence Platform</t>

    <t id="101">The rear command platform is now receiving the live tactical feed from Tharka's Cascade.</t>
    <t id="102">The 86th Escort Fleet is standing by in Tharka's Cascade.</t>
    <t id="103">Open the map and issue remote orders to the fleet.</t>
    <t id="111">HAT's 86th Escort Fleet conducts routine patrol and escort work in Tharka's Cascade.</t>
    <t id="112">Their job is to protect the sector's ships and stations, just as they once protected you.</t>
    <t id="113">With no ARG reinforcements coming, keep as many of them alive as you can.</t>
    <t id="114">You can pause the game at any time. Open the map now and take remote command.</t>

    <t id="201">Gatefall 02: Passing the Buck</t>
    <t id="202">You are remotely directing HAT's 86th Escort Fleet from the rear command platform. Use the map to issue orders.</t>
    <t id="211">Open the map and prepare to command the 86th Escort Fleet.</t>
    <t id="212">Destroy the Xenon fleet attacking the TEL freighter.</t>
    <t id="213">Clear all Xenon attack groups.</t>
    <t id="214">Proceed to the Argon forward command centre.</t>
    <t id="215">Deploy a satellite in deep space.</t>
    <t id="216">Forward Command Centre</t>
    <t id="217">Return to the rear command platform and open the map.</t>
    <t id="218">Defend the HAT station for 5 minutes.</t>
    <t id="219">Recover the classified-database keycard from the bar.</t>
    <t id="220">Go to the classified database.</t>
    <t id="221">Access the classified database.</t>
    <t id="222">Open the map and give the 86th Escort Fleet its final assignment.</t>
    <t id="223">Proceed to the navigation beacon deployment site in Family Zhin.</t>
    <t id="224">Downloading classified data and wiping camera footage and access logs...</t>
    <t id="225">Classified data download complete.</t>

    <t id="501">Morning, Commander. All quiet in Tharka's Cascade.</t>
    <t id="502">Morning, Rayna. Same as usual today—see if anyone needs a hand.</t>
    <t id="503">Same as yesterday, then? Remind me, how many Xenon did we bag on that "routine patrol"?</t>
    <t id="504">Lost count of the Ms and PEs. Plus a K—that one was a right pain.</t>
    <t id="505">After all that, ARG owes us something, surely. Maybe they could finally send those supplies they've been sitting on?</t>
    <t id="506">Uh...</t>
    <t id="507">The crews are saying the new Cerberuses are already coming apart at the seams—like someone hauled them straight out of a scrapyard.</t>
    <t id="508">I'll... see what else I can squeeze out of them. You know things haven't been the same between ARG and HAT since you went "legitimate".</t>
    <t id="509">I know. That's why they stuck us out here in the first place. Anyway, let's get the patrol done.</t>

    <t id="521">Mayday! Mayday! Under Xenon attack! Engines are down—requesting immediate assistance...</t>
    <t id="522">86th Escort Command here. Our ships are on the way. Hold on for one minute!</t>
    <t id="523">Don't worry, Commander. Our defence drones will make short work of the small fry, and the plasma turrets will stay on that Xenon K.</t>

    <t id="531">Commander, that TEL captain wants a word. Says you're old friends.</t>
    <t id="532">Sounds like one of my contacts in TEL. Put them through.</t>
    <t id="533">Well, well—if it isn't the commander of the 86th. I swear your fleet gets smaller every time I see it.</t>
    <t id="534">Hardly a match for your mighty escort fleet. Remind me—where did you find that optical camouflage of theirs?</t>
    <t id="535">All right, all right, walked right into that one. Seriously, though—thanks for the rescue.</t>
    <t id="536">If you really want to thank me, find me some better gear. That last batch was rough. Which pirate did you dig it up from?</t>
    <t id="537">Argon have been breathing down my neck lately. You're lucky I found you anything that could shoot. Besides, you're the one who insisted on frigates.</t>
    <t id="538">The Xenon are hitting harder by the day. Fighters don't last in Tharka's radiation, and you know what kind of shape HAT's 86th is in.</t>
    <t id="539">Lucky for them they've got a first-rate mug like you, funding your own job. Still don't know why you're so damn determined to protect the 86th.</t>

    <t id="541">Mayday! Mayday! The station is under Xenon attack, and they've brought capital ships!</t>
    <t id="542">HAT miner calling! Both us and the station are under Xenon attack! We need support!</t>
    <t id="543">Commander, the TEL freighter has its engines back. It's ready to withdraw.</t>
    <t id="544">Good. Send it towards the southern gate. Rayna, clear the hostiles around the miner, then double back and reinforce the station.</t>
    <t id="545">Understood. I'll cover their withdrawal, then head straight for the miner.</t>
    <t id="546">Copy that. Making for the gate now. I'll stay out of your way...</t>

    <t id="551">Thanks again! I'll see if I can cobble together a few more frigates for you.</t>
    <t id="552">Thank you. I've made it safely out of Tharka's Cascade.</t>
    <t id="553">Couldn't have done it without you. These Xenon capital ships are getting harder to deal with every day.</t>

    <t id="561">What a day... Say, Commander, what did they mean by "funding your own job" and "better gear"?</t>
    <t id="562">Uh... You must've strayed onto the wrong comm channel. I'm sure you misheard.</t>
    <t id="563">Then there's the fact that our entire operating budget for the past six months came from one private account. Any idea whose, Commander?</t>
    <t id="564">Uh... let's shelve that. Bigger problem: Xenon attacks are ramping up fast, both in size and frequency.</t>
    <t id="565">Capital-ship raids are practically routine now. Come to think of it, thank goodness for those plasma guns you somehow got hold of.</t>
    <t id="566">I get the feeling the Xenon are gearing up for something big. Even Argon patrols are being reinforced. We need more ships.</t>

    <t id="567">Frontier Commander, this is Syme, commander of the 86th Escort Fleet. I have an urgent report.</t>
    <t id="568">Oh? HAT's escort commander? Go on, then.</t>
    <t id="569">Xenon attacks on Tharka's Cascade are escalating. The threat to the core sectors, even Argon Prime, cannot be ignored.</t>
    <t id="570">HAT's still holding, isn't it? The sky hasn't fallen yet.</t>
    <t id="571">Yes, sir. But even limited support for the 86th would take enormous pressure off Argon's rear-area fleet.</t>
    <t id="572">Syme, I understand what the 86th means to you. They did save your life.</t>
    <t id="573">But this isn't something I can fix for you. I can't talk the Defence Ministry into supporting HAT, and you already knew that.</t>
    <t id="574">Still, you've done well lately, so here's some advice: bring them proof of a Xenon threat they can't ignore—and a little "gift" to sweeten it—and you might have a chance.</t>

    <t id="575">Rayna, I've got a job for you. A risky one. Head deep into the sector and find out what the Xenon are up to.</t>
    <t id="576">No problem—leave it to us. We'll keep some ships near the station in case they hit it again.</t>
    <t id="577">Be careful.</t>
    <t id="578">Commander, the satellite is in place. Deep-space telemetry is coming in now.</t>
    <t id="579">Good. Send it over. Let's see what the Xenon have tucked away in the depths of Tharka's Cascade.</t>
    <t id="581">Damn... That's a Xenon capital fleet. We're in trouble.</t>
    <t id="582">Rayna, pull back and hold the station. I'll call for reinforcements.</t>
    <t id="583">Frontier Commander, we've detected a massive concentration of Xenon I-class ships! The HAT station won't last long!</t>
    <t id="584">...I see them. You're right—this is serious. Have your people hold for five minutes. Reinforcements should make it by then.</t>
    <t id="585">Five minutes... All right. We'll do what we can.</t>

    <t id="586">Bad news, Commander! The station can't take much more!</t>
    <t id="587">Frontier Command, the Xenon capital fleet is on top of us! We can't hold much longer!</t>
    <t id="588">Syme, the Defence Ministry's order is for the 86th Escort Fleet to hold Tharka's Cascade to the last ship.</t>
    <t id="589">Your sacrifice will buy time for the Argon fleet to assemble and establish defences beyond the gate.</t>
    <t id="590">...</t>
    <t id="591">I'm sorry. I can't help you. One other thing—I seem to have left my classified-database key tucked under the lip of a table in the bar. Fetch it and return it to me.</t>
    <t id="592">Understood, Commander.</t>
    <t id="593">The classified-database key the Commander just "happened" to leave behind... Let's hope there's something useful in there.</t>
    <t id="594">There's plenty here. I already have a high-resolution map of Tharka's Cascade, and a map of ZYA space won't do much for us right now...</t>
    <t id="595">Yaki navigation protocol... It can use a navigation beacon to alter Xenon attack vectors... That's it!</t>
    <t id="596">But the nearest viable target is Family Zhin in ZYA space... There are civilians there too...</t>
    <t id="597">And sooner or later, the Xenon will just come back... Damn it. Save the 86th first; deal with the rest later.</t>
    <t id="598">Rayna, do you still have a navigation beacon?</t>
    <t id="599">One left, Commander. What are your orders?</t>
    <t id="600">Listen carefully. ARG command intends to sacrifice you, but I found a way to get you out alive.</t>
    <t id="601">I'm sending an encrypted package. Deploy the navigation beacon in ZYA's Family Zhin sector.</t>
    <t id="602">Copy that, Commander!</t>

    <t id="603">Beacon deployed. A whole swarm of Xenon just appeared by the gate in Family Zhin—looks like the same I-class ships that were heading for the station.</t>
    <t id="604">Commander, what exactly does that encrypted package do?</t>
    <t id="605">Orders from above. Need-to-know, and even I don't know the details... Besides, they're Xenon. Who knows what goes on in their heads?</t>
    <t id="606">But I do have one last assignment for you. ZYA and ARG are both about to be in deep trouble.</t>
    <t id="607">I've sent you a map of ZYA space. Follow their territory all the way to Heretic's End. I have Boron friends there—they'll take you in.</t>
    <t id="608">What about you, Commander? We have to take you with us!</t>
    <t id="609">I'm staying to hold back the Xenon, right to the end. Consider it repayment for saving my life.</t>
    <t id="610">Commander, you've already done more than enough for the 86th, but we...</t>
    <t id="611">As of today, you're all dead in the ARG database. The chains that bound you died with you.</t>
    <t id="612">Goodbye, Rayna. Goodbye, all of you. Go—go and claim the freedom that's yours... (communications cut)</t>
    <t id="613">Family Zhin flagship calling! Too many Xenon! Split needs reinforcements!</t>
    <t id="614">This is the rescue convoy! Split escorts are gone! Xenon are slaughtering civilians! Split requests reinforc—</t>
    <t id="615">This is Weapon Component Factory, section C02! Xenon detonated the munitions! Fire on one side, vacuum on the other—Split cannot hold...</t>
    <t id="616">Frontier Commander, sir. I retrieved the key you left in the bar.</t>
    <t id="617">You didn't use it, did you?</t>
    <t id="618">No. The cameras outside the database and the access logs will confirm it.</t>
    <t id="619">Good. And the 86th?</t>
    <t id="620">Lost with all hands. They destroyed a large Xenon force and bought Argon the time it needed. It's all in the combat logs.</t>
    <t id="621">A job well done, then... What's wrong, Syme? The 86th are gone, Rayna with them. Not happy?</t>
    <t id="622">(shakes head)</t>
    <t id="623">Or did switching on the killing machine yourself leave a bad taste, even with our oldest enemy on the receiving end?</t>
    <t id="624">(remains silent)</t>
    <t id="625">Never mind. For now... godspeed to the 86th.</t>
    <t id="626">And... good luck to ZYA as well.</t>

    <t id="1001">Gatefall 02: Passing the Buck Complete</t>
    <t id="1002">You completed Gatefall 02: Passing the Buck. With the Xenon fleet closing in, you refused to sacrifice the 86th, used a Yaki navigation protocol to redirect the assault into Family Zhin, and hid the truth from Argon.</t>
    <t id="1003">Campaign Failed</t>
    <t id="1004">You failed to complete Gatefall 02: Passing the Buck.</t>
    <t id="1005">Flagship Hull</t>
    <t id="1006">TEL Freighter Hull</t>
    <t id="1007">HAT Miner Hull</t>
    <t id="1008">HAT Outpost Hull</t>
    <t id="1009">86th Escort Survivors</t>
    <t id="1010">Xenon Ships Destroyed</t>
  </page>
  <page id="899902" title="Gatefall Chronicles" descr="Gatefall Chronicles custom Timelines campaign 04" voice="no">
    <t id="1">Gatefall 04: In the Same Boat</t>
    <t id="2">Background: The Xenon have pushed out of ZYA territory and seized Heretic's End. To reopen the lifeline to Morning Star's ice reserves, the Boron have entered a temporary alliance with the Terrans, who have come forward to suppress the anomalous Xenon threat.\n\nGameplay: Pilot a Boron Hydra Regal and protect the salvage ship as it recovers intelligence on a Xenon long-range weapon from a wrecked Guppy carrier. Build ships at the Tactical Production Platform, then command capital ships and fighters in an RTS-style assault on Xenon installations.\nNote: This scenario pays homage to the fifth Allied mission in Command &amp; Conquer: Red Alert 3 and makes extensive use of its soundtrack.</t>
    <t id="3">You are the Boron ambassador to Earth, trained in Terran military doctrine. In this operation, you serve as tactical officer of the Boron-Terran joint fleet, leading Terran expeditionary firepower and Boron escorts into Watchful Gaze.</t>
    <t id="4">Full Scenario</t>

    <t id="13">Ship AI</t>
    <t id="14">Player</t>
    <t id="15">Tinfika</t>
    <t id="16">Ledavi</t>
    <t id="17">Terran Tactical Officer</t>
    <t id="18">Hakapo</t>
    <t id="20">Hydra Regal</t>
    <t id="21">Guppy Carrier Wreck</t>
    <t id="22">Salvage Ship</t>
    <t id="23">Bluefin Leader</t>
    <t id="24">Bluefin Thresher</t>
    <t id="25">TER Syn</t>
    <t id="26">BOR Ray</t>
    <t id="27">Xenon Long-Range Artillery</t>
    <t id="28">Radar Ship</t>
    <t id="29">Xenon Ranging Radar Beta</t>
    <t id="30">Xenon M0 Shield Power Node Alpha</t>
    <t id="31">Xenon M0 Shield Power Node Beta</t>
    <t id="32">Xenon Deep Shipyard</t>
    <t id="33">Xenon Deep Wharf</t>
    <t id="34">Purplefin Leader</t>
    <t id="35">Purplefin Hydra</t>
    <t id="36">Purplefin Scimitar</t>
    <t id="37">Purplefin Katana (Anti-Fighter)</t>
    <t id="38">Mobile Base Packer</t>
    <t id="39">Tactical Production Platform</t>
    <t id="40">Menelaus' Reminiscence</t>
    <t id="41">TER Intervention Corps Tokyo</t>
    <t id="42">Xenon Jump Navigation Beacon</t>
    <t id="43">Xenon Long-Range Artillery Wreck</t>

    <t id="101">The Boron-Terran joint fleet is assembling in Watchful Gaze.</t>
    <t id="102">The salvage ship is recovering data from a Guppy carrier wreck.</t>
    <t id="103">Protect the salvage ship and recover intelligence on the Heretic's End blockade.</t>
    <t id="111">Heretic's End is locked down by a Xenon M0 variant.</t>
    <t id="112">The Boron need to reopen their lifeline to Morning Star ice resources.</t>
    <t id="113">The Terran expeditionary fleet has agreed to temporary cooperation, but its goal is clear: suppress the anomalous Xenon node.</t>

    <t id="201">Gatefall 04: In the Same Boat</t>
    <t id="202">Protect the Boron salvage ship while it recovers data from the Guppy wreck, destroy the Xenon radar ships in Heretic's End, cover the Tactical Production Platform's forward deployment, dismantle the Xenon power and shipbuilding network, and finally destroy the M0 long-range artillery ship.</t>
    <t id="211">Destroy the Xenon force threatening the salvage ship.</t>
    <t id="212">Protect the salvage ship for three minutes.</t>
    <t id="213">Enter Heretic's End with the Bluefin strike group.</t>
    <t id="214">Destroy the SE radar ship.</t>
    <t id="215">Destroy the second SE radar ship.</t>
    <t id="216">Destroy the first radar ship's escort force.</t>
    <t id="217">Destroy the second radar ship's escort force.</t>
    <t id="218">Protect the Mobile Base Packer for five minutes while it deploys the Tactical Production Platform.</t>
    <t id="219">Destroy the Xenon shipyard.</t>
    <t id="220">Destroy the Xenon wharf.</t>
    <t id="221">Destroy both Xenon solar power plants.</t>
    <t id="222">Destroy the remaining Xenon solar power plant before reinforcements arrive.</t>
    <t id="223">The tactical production platform is now linked to the player's build network, and the authorised blueprints plus Dolphin supply freighters are in place.</t>
    <t id="224">Destroy the Xenon long-range artillery ship: M0.</t>
    <t id="225">Destroy the second solar power plant.</t>
    <t id="226">Destroy the Xenon Deep-Space Shipyard</t>
    <t id="227">Destroy the Xenon deep-space shipyard to stop it from deploying more capital ships. This mission is independent of the Mutual Aid main mission.</t>
    <t id="228">Destroy the Xenon Deep-Space Wharf</t>
    <t id="229">Destroy the Xenon deep-space wharf to stop it from deploying more medium and small ships. This mission is independent of the Mutual Aid main mission.</t>

    <t id="501">Bluefin anti-fighter fleet reporting. We are under attack by Xenon capital ships.</t>
    <t id="502">Hakapo, where have you been? This is exactly when we needed you!</t>
    <t id="503">This is the ambassador posted to Earth. I brought fleet reinforcements with me.</t>
    <t id="511">So that gust finally blew you in... Still, all those years as a diplomat near Earth clearly were not wasted.</t>
    <t id="512">You know Terrans. Cold as deep water until someone says Xenon, then suddenly everyone is wide awake.</t>
    <t id="513">Ledavi sent me here so fast I barely had time to ask why. What is the situation?</t>
    <t id="514">As you can see, the Xenon have taken Heretic's End. Our water route is cut.</t>
    <t id="515">And the moment I think about us running out of water... no. I am not thinking about that.</t>
    <t id="516">The Xenon deployed some kind of long-range cannon. Our scouts were crippled before they could even get a proper look.</t>
    <t id="517">Then the Terrans heard the report and came running like someone put a battery in them, with capital ships attached.</t>
    <t id="518">I still do not love sharing a battlespace with people who treat artillery as a personality, but first we protect the salvage ship.</t>

    <t id="531">Sorry I am late. The Terrans asked me to bring along a few local specialties.</t>
    <t id="532">Took you long enough... We will need you for what comes next. The data from the carrier's black box is ready.</t>
    <t id="533">It appears the Xenon can hit our ships so precisely because they have deployed two mobile radar stations near the gate.</t>
    <t id="534">The data also shows that the Xenon cannon can only track L-class ships. It cannot accurately target fast small craft.</t>
    <t id="535">The carrier's fighters died triangulating those positions. We have to make this opportunity count.</t>

    <t id="541">That SE should be the radar ship we are looking for.</t>
    <t id="542">It is surrounded by a large number of Xenon ships. Destroying it will not be easy.</t>
    <t id="543">This is exactly what Bluefin does, and this time we have Terran weapons to back us up.</t>
    <t id="544">The second radar ship has a troublesome capital ship nearby... good thing I managed to call in a favor from the Terrans.</t>
    <t id="545">These Scimitars pair beautifully with plasma. They suit Purplefin perfectly.</t>

    <t id="551">Thank you for your cooperation, Boron friends. We can now study the vessel that breached the gate network in detail... an M0!</t>
    <t id="552">Structurally, it is unquestionably an M0, but it carries a long-range anti-ship weapon rather than a planet-killer.</t>
    <t id="553">The I-class ships around it are trouble enough. How many ships did you commit at Nopileos' Memorial?</t>
    <t id="554">The entire Commonwealth fleet was committed. Without Kyle Brennan, none of us would still be alive.</t>
    <t id="555">This time you have a full Terran equipment package behind you... but first, there is an unusual energy flow around the M0.</t>
    <t id="556">Something appears to be charging the M0's shields. This has escalated. I must report to the Queen and request deployment of a Tactical Production Platform.</t>

    <t id="561">Her Majesty has certainly spared no expense. She even sent one of our Mobile Base Packers.</t>
    <t id="562">A standard base packing cycle takes ten minutes. Deployment is faster, but it still needs five.</t>
    <t id="563">That is your assignment. The Tactical Production Platform must deploy without interruption.</t>
    <t id="564">Once complete, it will let us temporarily produce most ships from frigates through capital ships.</t>
    <t id="565">Given the current Xenon threat, the Intervention Corps authorises you to produce Syn-class destroyers.</t>
    <t id="566">That is generous. Even Terran allies do not always receive that privilege.</t>
    <t id="567">You carry the responsibility of destroying the Xenon. Terrans are never stingy toward their benefactors!</t>
    <t id="568">The Xenon capital ships have caught our scent. They do not look particularly hospitable.</t>
    <t id="569">Then let us teach them the proper meaning of hospitality!</t>
    <t id="570">That ship... could it be... a Xenon I? That Xenon I is enormous...</t>
    <t id="571">Far more impressive than the old veterans' descriptions from the gate-shutdown era!</t>
    <t id="572">I have to say, this Xenon I is much harder to kill than the K-class ships we usually face.</t>
    <t id="573">No wonder the Terrans get so jumpy when they keep dealing with beasts like these every day.</t>
    <t id="574">The Xenon assault is far more intense than expected. It seems we must enter the field ourselves.</t>
    <t id="575">These two carriers can repair your frigates and serve as the core of our positional defence.</t>
    <t id="576">So this is the Tactical Production Platform you deployed at such short notice. It would serve the Intervention Corps well on a deep-space expedition.</t>
    <t id="577">Necessity taught us how. During the Provinces Adrift era, the Boron moved from one water source to the next in much the same way.</t>
    <t id="578">This solar power plant should be one of the Xenon's power-harvesting facilities.</t>
    <t id="579">With microwave energy transmission, they can project a near-impenetrable iron curtain around the M0 and its escorts.</t>
    <t id="580">Our analysis suggests the two solar plants back each other up, and both are heavily guarded.</t>
    <t id="581">If we fail to destroy them together, the Xenon will concentrate their defences around the surviving plant. We need to take both down at the same time.</t>
    <t id="582">The Xenon use Heretic's End's rich mineral resources to produce more ships.</t>
    <t id="583">If we can destroy these facilities, we can greatly weaken the Xenon offensive.</t>
    <t id="584">The Xenon shipyard is down. Now every Xenon capital ship they lose is gone for good.</t>
    <t id="585">That should put an end to the Xenon small craft swarming us.</t>
    <t id="586">Long-range radar shows the Xenon are reinforcing the second solar power plant.</t>
    <t id="587">Every family has its troubles... Still, our survey fleet did manage to uncover something useful.</t>
    <t id="588">We struck a deal with the Terrans: mobile-base packing technology in exchange for Claytronics extraction technology.</t>
    <t id="589">Claytronics can substitute for any material you are missing, whether it is unique to Commonwealth or Terran production.</t>
    <t id="590">We installed the technology aboard the Dolphins. For every Dolphin you own, the base receives 500 units of Claytronics per minute.</t>
    <t id="591">The M0's iron curtain is down! All ships, attack!</t>
    <t id="592">The Xenon are getting desperate. They are teleporting fleets in from all over.</t>
    <t id="593">You mean... these Xenon... can teleport?</t>
    <t id="594">Yes. That is exactly why we came to investigate. Take down the M0 before they can bring in more forces!</t>
    <t id="595">Excellent! The Provinces Adrift have their water supply back! Wait... is that a navigation beacon?</t>
    <t id="596">Data recovered from the wreck indicates that the Xenon maintain a jump tower in their core sectors, coordinating fleet transfers.</t>
    <t id="597">The destination of each jump is selected through navigation beacons distributed across the network.</t>
    <t id="598">We intercepted several Xenon scouts heading for the Solar System. It seems they were placing these beacons... Ledavi, you do not look well.</t>
    <t id="599">This is bad! Xenon scouts were sighted repeatedly in Kingdom End not long ago, and we never eliminated all of them...</t>
    <t id="600">There is still time to repair the damage. You must notify Her Majesty immediately!</t>
    <t id="601">Look! A Xenon scout, heading toward Argon space!</t>
    <t id="602">The Argon claim to be concentrating on defence of their core territory while abandoning even Heretic's End. Let us hope they truly have been making an effort...</t>

    <t id="1001">In the Same Boat Complete</t>
    <t id="1002">You completed In the Same Boat: recovered the Guppy wreck intelligence, destroyed both Xenon radar ships, established the Tactical Production Platform, cut the Xenon shipbuilding and power network, and destroyed the M0 long-range artillery ship.</t>
    <t id="1003">Scenario Failed</t>
    <t id="1004">The salvage ship was destroyed and the wreck data could not be recovered.</t>
    <t id="1005">Salvage Ship Hull</t>
    <t id="1006">Player Hull</t>
    <t id="1007">Auto-cleared Xenon Remnants</t>
    <t id="1008">Mobile Base Packer Hull</t>
    <t id="1009">The Mobile Base Packer was destroyed and the Tactical Production Platform could not deploy.</t>
    <t id="1010">The Tactical Production Platform was destroyed, and the joint fleet lost its forward base.</t>
    <t id="1011">Xenon Capital Ships Destroyed</t>
    <t id="1012">Each registered Xenon L/XL capital ship destroyed in combat adds 10 points. Scripted cleanup does not count.</t>
    <t id="1013">Scenario Time</t>
    <t id="1014">Time Score</t>
    <t id="1015">A time of 40 minutes or less scores 200; 140 minutes or more scores 0; times in between are mapped linearly.</t>
    <t id="1016">Final Score</t>
    <t id="1017">The final score combines Xenon capital-ship kills, time, and the Tactical Production Platform's remaining hull.</t>
    <t id="1018">Tactical Production Platform Hull</t>
    <t id="1019">The platform's remaining hull from 0% to 100% maps directly to 0 to 100 points.</t>
  </page>
  <page id="899903" title="Gatefall Chronicles" descr="Gatefall Chronicles campaign 05" voice="no">
    <t id="1">Gatefall 05: Judgement Day</t><t id="2">Infiltrate Argon space, deploy a strategic anchor and bring a Second Fleet production node online.</t><t id="3">Phase 0–4 vertical slice. Completion intentionally awards zero stars.</t><t id="4">Phase 4 Preview</t>
    <t id="10">Hatikvah's Choice</t><t id="11">A campaign-authored strategic theatre.</t><t id="12">Argon Prime</t><t id="13">Hatikvah's Faith</t><t id="14">Nopileos Memorial</t><t id="15">Second Fleet Command Core</t><t id="20">Xenon F</t><t id="21">Xenon CPU Ship</t><t id="31">Argon Wharf</t><t id="32">Argon Shipyard</t><t id="33">Argon Administration Centre</t><t id="34">Strategic Anchor</t>
    <t id="101">Pass through the Argon expedition review.</t><t id="102">Cross Argon Prime without being destroyed.</t><t id="103">Deploy the first strategic anchor and initialise the manufacturing chain.</t>
    <t id="201">Assemble 1 Xenon I</t><t id="202">Assemble 2 Xenon K</t><t id="203">Assemble 10 Xenon PE</t><t id="204">Assemble 10 Xenon B</t><t id="205">Assemble 20 Xenon F</t><t id="206">Assemble 30 Xenon M</t>
    <t id="211">Accepting this production order removes all other orders. The selected ships appear near the CPU ship immediately. New orders become available after two minutes.</t>
    <t id="301">Judgement Day</t><t id="302">Establish the first Second Fleet strategic anchor inside Argon space.</t><t id="311">Evade Argon reconnaissance and reach the Argon Prime transit point.</t><t id="312">Cross Argon Prime.</t><t id="313">Cross Hatikvah's Faith.</t><t id="314">Reach the Nopileos Memorial anchor point.</t><t id="315">Complete three CPU-ship production orders.</t>
    <t id="501">Supervisor instance online. Continuity verified. Establish the first strategic anchor.</t><t id="511">The Argon northern expedition is departing under full public review.</t><t id="512">Its confidence has emptied the core while preserving the appearance of strength.</t><t id="521">Argon Prime identified. Shipbuilding and administrative targets recorded.</t><t id="522">Transit to Hatikvah's Faith complete. Maintain low power.</t><t id="531">Nopileos Memorial ahead. Proceed to the anchor point.</t><t id="541">Strategic anchor deployed. Correcting the failure recorded at this monument.</t><t id="551">CPU ship authorised. Complete three assembly orders to verify the manufacturing chain.</t><t id="552">Assembly order complete.</t>
    <t id="1001">Phase 4 Preview Complete</t><t id="1002">Production orders completed</t><t id="1003">This preview ends after the manufacturing tutorial and intentionally awards zero score.</t>
  </page>
</language>
